{"tossups":[{"question":"This text uses the mysterious word “ziff,” which presumably refers to a precious metal of some kind. This text uses the word “curelom” to refer to an unknown animal which some people have theorized is a mammoth. Critics of this text often point to its use of the French word “adieu” in the line “Brethren, adieu.” This text’s usages of the word “Christ” and its references to things like (*) elephants and wheat are among the anachronisms that are argued to show this text to be inauthentic. This text is the source of a word meaning “honeybee” in the language of the Jaredites; that word, Deseret, was proposed as a name for the state of Utah. For 10 points, name this text that was supposedly translated from “reformed Egyptian” by Joseph Smith.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>Book of Mormon<\/b><\/u>","answer":"<b><u>Book of Mormon<\/b><\/u>","category":"Religion","subcategory":"Religion","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":1},{"question":"A woman says this word before arriving with a jewel-encrusted object in a commercial in which Steve Carell [kuh-REL] tries and fails to say this word. This word is interjected during the line “a little crazy, but I’m just your type” in a guest verse from Ed Sheeran’s song “South of the Border.” This word was originated by the RuPaul’s Drag Race contestant (*) Laganja Estranja [luh-GON-juh ess-TRON-juh]. This word is spoken by two pigeons and a bunch of restaurant patrons in a 2019 Super Bowl ad for Pepsi that ends with a clip from the song “I Like It.” In 2019, the USPTO cited the Kardashians’ use of this word in rejecting an application. Cardi B unsuccessfully tried to trademark, for 10 points, what variant of the word “okay”?","formatted_answer":"<b><u>okurr<\/b><\/u>r [reject “okay”]","answer":"<b><u>okurr<\/b><\/u>r [reject “okay”]","category":"Trash","subcategory":"Trash","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":2},{"question":"This author coined the word “illth” as the opposite of “wealth.” This person defined the word “restoration” as “the most total destruction which a building can suffer” in a passage criticizing the work of contemporaries like Eugène Viollet-le-Duc [oo-ZHEN vyoh-leh-luh-DOOK]. This author quoted lines about a “spendthrift crocus” and “cruel, crawling foam” to characterize a phrase that this author used to refer to a poetic (*) falseness influenced by emotion. The words “force,” “fortitude” and “fortune” inspired the title of this author’s Fors Clavigera. This writer coined the phrase “pathetic fallacy” in a book written primarily as a defense of J. M. W. Turner. For 10 points, name this Victorian art critic who wrote The Seven Lamps of Architecture and Modern Painters.","formatted_answer":"John <b><u>Ruskin<\/b><\/u>","answer":"John <b><u>Ruskin<\/b><\/u>","category":"Literature","subcategory":"American Literature","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":3},{"question":"Steve Potter combined the word for this type of organism with the word “robot” to refer to robots controlled by rat neurons. As the etymology of its name suggests, the atemoya is this type of organism. The term “grex,” from the Latin for “flock,” indicates that a plant is this type of organism. Organisms of this type can also be named using the prefix (*) “notho-.” G. H. Shull replaced the misleading term “heterozygosis” with “heterosis” to refer to a phenomenon also called these organisms’ “vigor.” In botany, these organisms are often named by inserting a multiplication sign between two scientific names. Portmanteau words like “beefalo” and “liger” refer to, for 10 points, what organisms whose parents come from different taxonomic groups?","formatted_answer":"<b><u>hybrid<\/b><\/u>s [prompt on <u>cross<\/u>es; prompt on <u>cross<\/u>-bred organisms; prompt on <u>cross<\/u>-fertilized organisms; accept <b><u>hybrid<\/b><\/u> vigor] (Potter’s robots are called “hybrots.” The atemoya is a hybrid of the sugar-apple and the cherimoya, and its name is a portmanteau of “cherimoya” and a word for a sugar-apple.)","answer":"<b><u>hybrid<\/b><\/u>s [prompt on crosses; prompt on cross-bred organisms; prompt on cross-fertilized organisms; accept <b><u>hybrid<\/b><\/u> vigor] (Potter’s robots are called “hybrots.” The atemoya is a hybrid of the sugar-apple and the cherimoya, and its name is a portmanteau of “cherimoya” and a word for a sugar-apple.)","category":"Science","subcategory":"Biology","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":4},{"question":"Due to an incident involving this word, Martin Lucas and Robert Barker were called before the Star Chamber and fined 300 pounds. Numerous lines beginning with this word, followed by words like “beginning,” “winning,” and “spinning,” are sung by Adrienne Lenker in a song by Big Thief. This word is spelled the same as a German word for “necessity” used in art history to refer to an invented name for an (*) artist whose true name is unknown. A lecturer uses the sentence “This suit is black” to try to explain a joking use of this word to Borat in the film Borat. This word was accidentally omitted from Exodus 20:14 in the so-called “Wicked Bible.” This is the three-letter name of a logic gate that outputs 0 for 1 and vice versa. For 10 points, name this word that negates the meaning of a sentence.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>not<\/b><\/u> [accept <b><u>Notname<\/b><\/u>] (The Wicked Bible accidentally omitted the “not” in “Thou shalt not commit adultery.”)","answer":"<b><u>not<\/b><\/u> [accept <b><u>Notname<\/b><\/u>] (The Wicked Bible accidentally omitted the “not” in “Thou shalt not commit adultery.”)","category":"Fine Arts","subcategory":"Visual Fine Arts","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":5},{"question":"This artist photographed someone holding a bag with the letter “F” in front of the MoMA, implicitly turning the museum’s name into “Museum of Modern Fart.” In another work by this artist, the permanence of the word “apple” on a brass plate is contrasted with an actual apple that was left to rot. A work by this artist includes a ladder that the viewer must climb before using a magnifying glass to look at the word (*) “yes”; that work impressed this artist’s future third husband. The word “why” is repeated ad nauseam in the song “Why” from this artist’s 1970 debut album, on which she was backed by her eponymous “plastic” band. For 10 points, name this Japanese conceptual artist who was married to John Lennon.","formatted_answer":"Yoko <b><u>Ono<\/b><\/u> [accept Plastic <b><u>Ono<\/b><\/u> Band]","answer":"Yoko <b><u>Ono<\/b><\/u> [accept Plastic <b><u>Ono<\/b><\/u> Band]","category":"Fine Arts","subcategory":"Auditory Fine Arts","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":6},{"question":"A passage about the radio writer Goodman Ace that is filled with these expressions is quoted in a paper that defines “first meaning” as meaning that is systematic, shared, and prepared; that paper about these expressions is by Donald Davidson. The use of these expressions was the signature trait of Emily Litella, a character played by (*) Gilda Radner on SNL. These expressions are sometimes named for Shakespeare’s Dogberry, but are more commonly named for Lydia Languish’s guardian in Richard Brinsley Sheridan’s The Rivals, who often uses phrases like “the very pine-apple of politeness.” For 10 points, name these expressions in which an incorrect word is substituted for a similar-sounding word.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>malaprop<\/b><\/u>isms [accept <b><u>Dogberry<\/b><\/u>isms before “Dogberry”; prompt on speech <u>error<\/u>s]","answer":"<b><u>malaprop<\/b><\/u>isms [accept <b><u>Dogberry<\/b><\/u>isms before “Dogberry”; prompt on speech errors]","category":"Literature","subcategory":"British Literature","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":7},{"question":"One usage of this word is said to have been introduced by Private Aubrey Eberhardt in reference to a 1939 film starring Chief Thundercloud. Controversially, this word was used to refer to a person who was also known by the nickname “Cakebread” during an event in which a man repeated this word after saying “for God and country.” Some Native American activists objected to this word’s use as a (*) codeword for the objective of Operation Neptune Spear, the 2011 operation to kill Osama bin Laden. Goyaałé [koh-yah-leh] is the Chiricahua [CHIRR-ih-KAH-wuh] name for a leader more commonly known by this name, who led raids in Mexico and the U.S. in the 1880s. For 10 points, what Apache leader’s name is often shouted by people jumping from a great height?","formatted_answer":"<b><u>Geronimo<\/b><\/u>","answer":"<b><u>Geronimo<\/b><\/u>","category":"Science","subcategory":"Chemistry","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":8},{"question":"Members of this ethnic group used a parrot egg as a signal for a monarch to either abdicate or commit ritual suicide as part of a symbolic non-verbal communication system called àrokò [ah-roh-koh]. The word “Nagos” [NAH-gohz] refers to members of this ethnic group, particularly from the kingdom of Ketu [KAY-too], who were enslaved in the late 19th century. The name of this ethnic group is a (*) Hausa [HOW-suh] exonym that originally referred specifically to the Oyo Empire. Lucumí [loo-koo-MEE], a colonial Spanish term for these people, is also an alternate name for a religion in which Catholic saints are syncretized with this group’s deities, the orishas [oh-ree-shahs]. For 10 points, name this West African ethnic group whose religion is the basis for New World religions like Santería [sahn-tay-REE-ah].","formatted_answer":"<b><u>Yoruba<\/b><\/u> [or Ọmọ <b><u>Odùduwà<\/b><\/u>; or Ọmọ <b><u>Káàárò-oòjíire<\/b><\/u>]","answer":"<b><u>Yoruba<\/b><\/u> [or Ọmọ <b><u>Odùduwà<\/b><\/u>; or Ọmọ <b><u>Káàárò-oòjíire<\/b><\/u>]","category":"Religion","subcategory":"Religion","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":9},{"question":"This person chastised Randolph Barnhouse for using the word “choate” [KOH-ate] to mean the opposite of “inchoate” [in-KOH-ate], comparing it to the use of “gruntled” as the opposite of “disgruntled.” This person complained that “words no longer have meaning” in a 2015 text that memorably uses the phrase “interpretive (*) jiggery-pokery.” This person often attempted to persuade colleagues by sending them memoranda called “Ninograms,” a reference to his nickname “Nino.” This person wrote that the word “militia” in the Second Amendment refers to the “body of all citizens capable of military service” in the majority opinion in DC v. Heller. For 10 points, name this originalist Supreme Court justice who died in 2016.","formatted_answer":"Antonin (Gregory) <b><u>Scalia<\/b><\/u>","answer":"Antonin (Gregory) <b><u>Scalia<\/b><\/u>","category":"History","subcategory":"American History","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":10},{"question":"The question of whether this word refers to things that exist or not is debated by Argle and Bargle in a dialogue by David and Stephanie Lewis. A plot thread from Yellow Submarine that plays on the strangeness of this word ends with Ringo saying that he has half of one of these things, having given the other half to Jeremy. A pun on this four-letter word and its homophone is made by Benoit Blanc at the end of a (*) dessert-inspired speech that repeats this word in the film Knives Out. MathWorld defines this word as a topological structure that prevents an object from being continuously shrunk to a point. “Genus” can be informally defined as the number of these things a surface has, which is why a torus has genus 1. For 10 points, people often debate whether a straw has one or two of what things?","formatted_answer":"<b><u>hole<\/b><\/u>s","answer":"<b><u>hole<\/b><\/u>s","category":"Philosophy","subcategory":"Philosophy","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":11},{"question":"Many listicles dubiously claim that a language from this island uses the word tingo [TEENG-goh] to mean “to borrow items from a neighbor one by one until they have nothing left.” A local language’s name for this island indicates that it is bigger than a similarly-named member of the Bass Islands. Two crescent-shaped reimiro [ray-MEE-roh] ornaments are among the two dozen wooden items from this island that display a reversed boustrophedon [BOOST-ruh-FEE-dun] script. This island is home to the (*) undeciphered Rongorongo [RONG-goh-RONG-goh] script. Jacob Roggeveen [YAK-ohb ROH-huh-ven] gave this island its English name, which references the fact that it was discovered on April 5, 1722. For 10 points, name this Polynesian island home to many moai [MOH-eye], which are monolithic statues of human figures.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>Easter<\/b><\/u> Island [or <b><u>Rapa Nui<\/b><\/u>; or Isla de <b><u>Pascua<\/b><\/u>] (“Rapa Nui” means “big Rapa,” which distinguishes it from the smaller Rapa Island.)","answer":"<b><u>Easter<\/b><\/u> Island [or <b><u>Rapa Nui<\/b><\/u>; or Isla de <b><u>Pascua<\/b><\/u>] (“Rapa Nui” means “big Rapa,” which distinguishes it from the smaller Rapa Island.)","category":"Geography","subcategory":"Geography","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":12},{"question":"James Murray complained that this poet “constantly used words without regard to their proper meaning” and thus “added greatly to the difficulties of the [Oxford English Dictionary].” This poet apologizes for forgetting the rest of the words after reciting the phrase “the lights sank to rest” in the earliest known phonograph reading of a major author’s voice. This author mistakenly thought that a vulgar word for a woman’s genitals actually referred to part of a (*) nun’s habit, and included it in his verse drama about a silk-winding girl. This poet’s love of onomatopoeia is illustrated by his use of the exclamation “Gr-r-r,” addressed to Brother Lawrence, in his “Soliloquy of the Spanish Cloister.” For 10 points, name this author of Pippa Passes and dramatic monologues like “My Last Duchess.”","formatted_answer":"Robert <b><u>Browning<\/b><\/u>","answer":"Robert <b><u>Browning<\/b><\/u>","category":"Literature","subcategory":"British Literature","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":13},{"question":"This word, used ironically, is the title of a 2019 book by Andrew Doyle, written from the perspective of Doyle’s persona Titania McGrath. Georgia Anne Muldrow wrote a song that helped popularize this word, Erykah Badu’s “Master Teacher.” The use of this word in Childish Gambino’s “Redbone,” in which it serves as a warning to people with cheating partners, was the reason that Jordan Peele used the song at the beginning of Get Out. This word originated as a past (*) participle that is often used with intensified continuative habitual aspect in AAVE [AH-vay]. A compound that combines this word with “scold” has a similar meaning to the acronym “SJW.” For 10 points, name this word, now mostly used pejoratively, which means “aware of social inequities.”","formatted_answer":"<b><u>woke<\/b><\/u> [accept stay <b><u>woke<\/b><\/u>]","answer":"<b><u>woke<\/b><\/u> [accept stay <b><u>woke<\/b><\/u>]","category":"Trash","subcategory":"Trash","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":14},{"question":"This is the second-last suffix in the foreign word that introduces the “Dream Fugue” section of Thomas De Quincey’s “The English Mail-Coach.” A 1956 Dior perfume whose name ends with this suffix is widely considered one of the best replications of the lily-of-the-valley scent. A word ending with this suffix describes the uppermost register of a (*) woodwind instrument. Root words are immediately followed by the same words with this suffix to help produce the tongue-twisting effect of the aria “Largo al factotum.” A rank superior to that of a five-star general ends in this suffix and has been used by Chiang Kai-shek and Francisco Franco. For 10 points, name this Italian superlative suffix that can be added to piano and forte in music.","formatted_answer":"-<b><u>issimo<\/b><\/u> [or -<b><u>issima<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>tumultuosissimamente<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>Diorissimo<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>altissimo<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>generalissimo<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>pianissimo<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>fortissimo<\/b><\/u>]","answer":"-<b><u>issimo<\/b><\/u> [or -<b><u>issima<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>tumultuosissimamente<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>Diorissimo<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>altissimo<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>generalissimo<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>pianissimo<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>fortissimo<\/b><\/u>]","category":"Fine Arts","subcategory":"Auditory Fine Arts","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":15},{"question":"This person wrote “maybe we live in rarefied circles” in an apology for the use of a baseball term which is also a slur against Mexican people. A 2006 documentary by Patrick Creadon focuses on an event hosted by this person that prominently featured the word “Zola-esque.” People like Elizabeth Gorski have criticized this co-worker of Sam (*) Ezersky [uh-ZER-skee] for not doing enough to achieve gender parity and for tokenizing testers like Claire Muscat. Michael Sharp, using the pseudonym Rex Parker, often calls for this person to be replaced. This successor of Eugene T. Maleska is a mustachioed table tennis enthusiast who hosts a weekly puzzle segment on NPR’s Weekend Edition.  For 10 points, name this editor of the New York Times crossword.","formatted_answer":"Will <b><u>Shortz<\/b><\/u> [or William F. <b><u>Shortz<\/b><\/u>]","answer":"Will <b><u>Shortz<\/b><\/u> [or William F. <b><u>Shortz<\/b><\/u>]","category":"Science","subcategory":"Other Science","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":16},{"question":"This word is written in all caps with an exclamation mark in a chapter that reports an experiment involving Lindt truffles and Hershey’s kisses; that chapter about this word is from Dan Ariely’s Predictably Irrational. The Communist Manifesto mocks phrases containing this adjective as bourgeois “brave words” that are meaningless when opposed to “the Communistic abolition of buying and selling.” Richard Stallman mentions (*) beer in his disambiguation of the two common meanings of this adjective. Robert Heinlein’s The Moon Is a Harsh Mistress popularized a phrase containing this adjective that is used to explain the concept of opportunity cost. For 10 points, the acronym “TANSTAAFL” stands for “there ain’t no such thing as [what kind of] lunch”?","formatted_answer":"<b><u>free<\/b><\/u> [accept “<b><u>free<\/b><\/u> as in speech, not as in beer”; accept “there ain’t no such thing as a <b><u>free<\/b><\/u> lunch”]","answer":"<b><u>free<\/b><\/u> [accept “<b><u>free<\/b><\/u> as in speech, not as in beer”; accept “there ain’t no such thing as a <b><u>free<\/b><\/u> lunch”]","category":"Social Science","subcategory":"Social Science","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":17},{"question":"A co-creator of this game, Glenn Wichman, has tried to popularize the phrase “consequence persistence” to describe a property of this game. A word that references this game is the subject of the “Berlin Interpretation,” which uses properties like non-modality to define that word. Several video games imitate this game in using the phrase “Amulet of (*) Yendor,” which references a wizard whose name was created by reversing the name “Rodney.” A word that includes the name of this game is used to characterize Angband, NetHack, and other games that use procedurally generated levels and permadeath. For 10 points, name this 1980 dungeon crawl RPG whose name is followed by the suffix “-like” to refer to a genre of similar games.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>Rogue<\/b><\/u> [accept <b><u>roguelike<\/b><\/u>s]","answer":"<b><u>Rogue<\/b><\/u> [accept <b><u>roguelike<\/b><\/u>s]","category":"Fine Arts","subcategory":"Visual Fine Arts","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":18},{"question":"A woman in this novel rebukes her daughter by telling her that “careless words … make people love you a little less.” The adjective “dustgreen,” which describes trees in this novel’s opening paragraph, is one of its many invented compound words. This novel capitalizes the phrase “Two Thoughts” when describing the thoughts a character thinks while stirring (*) jam at a factory. In this novel, “pocket money” is spelled “porketmunny” to represent the accent of a snack vendor who molests one of the protagonists. This novel invents the words “orangedrink” and “lemondrink” to describe that vendor, who molests a character who breaks the “Love Laws” by having sex with his sister. For 10 points, the fraternal twins Estha and Rahel are the protagonists of what novel by Arundhati Roy?","formatted_answer":"The <b><u>God of Small Things<\/b><\/u>","answer":"The <b><u>God of Small Things<\/b><\/u>","category":"Literature","subcategory":"World Literature","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":19},{"question":"A term for a style of writing that uses these words was coined by Paul Jennings in a series of three 1966 articles in Punch. The sci-fi author Poul Anderson wrote an explanation of atomic theory using only words of this type. These words, often contrasted with inkhorn words, are included along with “familiar,” “concrete,” “single,” and “short” words in H. W. (*) Fowler’s list of five rules for vocabulary. In “Politics and the English Language,” Orwell says that “bad writers” nearly always believe that unnecessary words like “expedite” and “ameliorate” are grander than these words. The words “damn” and “piss” contradict the stereotype that profane words in English tend to be this type of word. For 10 points, name these words that many English style guides prefer to words derived from Romance.","formatted_answer":"Anglo-<b><u>Saxon<\/b><\/u> words in modern English [or <b><u>Old English<\/b><\/u> words in modern English; or <b><u>Germanic<\/b><\/u> words in modern English; accept any descriptions indicating words that are <b><u>natively English<\/b><\/u> or are <b><u>not borrowed<\/b><\/u> from other languages or are <b><u>not loanword<\/b><\/u>s]","answer":"Anglo-<b><u>Saxon<\/b><\/u> words in modern English [or <b><u>Old English<\/b><\/u> words in modern English; or <b><u>Germanic<\/b><\/u> words in modern English; accept any descriptions indicating words that are <b><u>natively English<\/b><\/u> or are <b><u>not borrowed<\/b><\/u> from other languages or are <b><u>not loanword<\/b><\/u>s]","category":"Current Events","subcategory":"Current Events","packetNumber":7,"questionNumber":20}],"bonuses":[]}
